<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paper Reading on ztqakita's Blog</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/</link><description>Recent content in Paper Reading on ztqakita's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 06:00:20 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[CN] Task representations in neural networks trained to perform many cognitive tasks</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/task_representation_cognitive_tasks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/task_representation_cognitive_tasks/</guid><description> Yang, G.R., Joglekar, M.R., Song, H.F. et al. Task representations in neural networks trained to perform many cognitive tasks. Nat Neurosci 22, 297–306 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-018-0310-2
Abstract</description></item><item><title>[DL &amp; CN] Placing language in an integrated understanding system: Next steps toward human-level performance in neural language models</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/integrated_understanding_system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/integrated_understanding_system/</guid><description>McClelland, James L., et al. &amp;ldquo;Placing language in an integrated understanding system: Next steps toward human-level performance in neural language models.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 117.42 (2020): 25966-25974.
Abstract For humans, language is a part of a system for understanding and communication about situations. There are some domain-general principles of biological neural network:
connection-based learning distributed representation context-sensitive mutual constraint satisfaction What they propose: the organization of the brain&amp;rsquo;s distributed understanding system, which includes a fast learning system that addresses the memory problem.</description></item><item><title>[BIC] A brain-inspired computational model for spatio-temporal information processing</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/reservoir_decision_making/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/reservoir_decision_making/</guid><description>Lin, Xiaohan, et al. &amp;ldquo;A brain-inspired computational model for spatio-temporal information processing.&amp;rdquo; Neural Networks 143 (2021): 74-87.
Abstract Current method: Explicit feature extraction, which requires lots of labeled data. Novel brain-inspired computational model: Reservoir Decision-making Network (RDMN) A reservoir model: projects complex spatio-temporal patterns into spatially separated neural representations via its recurrent dynamics. (regarded it as SVM) A decision-making model: reads out neural representations via integrating information over time.</description></item><item><title>[BIC] Push-pull Feedback Implements Hierarchical Information Retrieval Efficiently</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/push-pull_feedback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/push-pull_feedback/</guid><description>Liu, Xiao, et al. &amp;ldquo;Push-pull feedback implements hierarchical information retrieval efficiently.&amp;rdquo; Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 32 (2019): 5701-5710.
Front Word To understand this paper, you need a strong neuroscience background, especially knowing the Hopfield model and Hebbian theory. So before reading this paper, please preview the theories mentioned above!
To be honest, I still cannot understand the details quite well LoL :)
Abstract In addition to feedforward connections, there exist abundant feedback connections in a neural pathway.</description></item></channel></rss>