<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paper Reading on ztqakita's Blog</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/</link><description>Recent content in Paper Reading on ztqakita's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:00:20 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[DL &amp; CN] Placing language in an integrated understanding system: Next steps toward human-level performance in neural language models</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/integrated_understanding_system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/integrated_understanding_system/</guid><description>Abstract For humans, language is a part of a system for understanding and communication about situations. There are some domain-general principles of biological neural network:
connection-based learning distributed representation context-sensitive mutual constraint satisfaction What they propose: the organization of the brain&amp;rsquo;s distributed understanding system, which includes a fast learning system that addresses the memory problem.
Principles of Neural Computation A certain principles in PDP(parallel distributed processing) framework is the idea that cognition depends on mutual constraint satisfaction.</description></item><item><title>[BIC] A brain-inspired computational model for spatio-temporal information processing</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/reservoir_decision_making/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/reservoir_decision_making/</guid><description>Abstract Current method: Explicit feature extraction, which requires lots of labeled data. Novel brain-inspired computational model: Reservoir Decision-making Network (RDMN) A reservoir model: projects complex spatio-temporal patterns into spatially separated neural representations via its recurrent dynamics. (regarded it as SVM) A decision-making model: reads out neural representations via integrating information over time. Tasks: Looming pattern discrimination Gait recognition Event-based gait recognition The model Overview Summary: A spatio-temporal pattern is first processed by the reservoir module and then read out by the decision-making module.</description></item><item><title>[BIC] Push-pull Feedback Implements Hierarchical Information Retrieval Efficiently</title><link>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/push-pull_feedback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://ztqakita.github.io/posts/paper-reading/push-pull_feedback/</guid><description>Front Word To understand this paper, you need a strong neuroscience background, especially knowing the Hopfield model and Hebbian theory. So before reading this paper, please preview the theories mentioned above!
To be honest, I still cannot understand the details quite well LoL :)
Abstract In addition to feedforward connections, there exist abundant feedback connections in a neural pathway. This paper investigate the role of feedback in hierarchical information retrieval.</description></item></channel></rss>